# Anjali Malik

malik.anjali79@gmail.com | +91 9899927255 | Delhi, India



#### Bio

A driven and skilled Human Resources professional with 6 years of comprehensive experience driving key initiatives in HR verticals like Compensation, Benefits and Well-being. Driven to enhance employees' workplace experience by data driven and yet empathetic, employee centric practices. Seeking challenging roles and hoping to create value via sustainable business solutions

#### **Education**

**Tata Institute of Social Sciences**Mumbai, India
Master of Arts in Human Resources Management & Labour Relations (Gold Medalist, Rank 1)
2017-2019

Banasthali University

B. Tech in Information Technology (First division)

Rajasthan, India
2010-2014

N.K. Bagrodia Public School Delhi, India

Class XII (Full Merit-based Academic Scholarship) 2010

Queen Mary's SchoolDelhi, IndiaClass X (Ranked 1st)2008

#### **Work Experience**

Reckitt Benckiser Co. August 2023 – Present

Rewards Lead, South Asia

- Designing the **rewards and talent philosophy** for an evolving **global capability center (GCC)** workforce across functions like Finance, HR Shared Services etc., focusing on internal parity, other global hubs and India market parity
- Worked on a **local market variable pay program re-hash** and implementation for India Sales function to account for local market nuances like granular business performance metric considerations
- **Aided talent retention efforts** in key functions by focused interventions: Conducted gender pay gap analysis & consulted on talent interventions where attrition was not financially driven, helping to reduce employees below range from 13% to 5%
- Led a **benefits re-design and roadmap project,** to review the existing benefits offerings by conducting market studies, internal surveys and leveraging leadership insights to suit futuristic employee needs
  - o Successfully revamped Insurance programs including vendor negotiations, implementation and communication
  - o Proactively led policy design and roll-out of benefits for blue collar workforce and other programs like compassionate leave, domestic travel policy etc.
- Other projects: Led Bangladesh salary restructuring in line with statutory compliances, managed global mobility- offers and benefits, HR transformation projects and transition- online people cost planning, mid-year adjustments etc.

#### **Deloitte Consulting Pvt. Ltd.**

May 2019 – August 2023

Assistant Manager, Total Rewards (Compensation & Benefits)

September 2021 – August 2023

Managing dual responsibility of: Compensation strategy & management based on external market ecosystem and internal alignment for Deloitte's Audit and Assurance vertical and firm-wide **Benefits & Well-being** program design and deployment (~80,000 employees)

- Facilitated benefits review and alignment in M&A scenarios, working on a low-cost benefits program design
- Facilitated market study of variable bonus payout trends amongst competitors across industries to supplement and
  validate annual market data received from benchmarking partner. Leveraged surveys, interviews and recruitment/ sourcing
  team inputs to analyze offer and hike letters for proposed changes with regards to bonus ranges, inclusion of benefits cost in
  CTC and other market practices

Analyst/ Sr. Analyst, Total Rewards (Compensation)

May 2019 - August 2021 (Promoted Sept. 2020)

- **Designed compensation ranges** across roles basis market data analysis, internal business priorities & talent landscape considerations
- Managed the compensation strategy for new job families within the business- job role description creation, liaising with third-party vendors for job mapping and salary benchmarking, creation of hiring ranges and fitments considering internal parity
- Initiated a deferred bonus and attrition correlation analysis to drive compensation structure change enabling firm savings
- Created a framework of using multiple anchors for year-end compensation analysis (data-driven actionable insights)

Curriculum Vitae Anjali Malik

## **Industrial Development Bank of India** (Assistant Manager)

Oct 2016 - Jan 2017

• Responsible for streamlined retail banking operations and customer management

# State Bank of India (Assistant Manager)

Dec 2014 - May 2015

Acquired knowledge across domains (personal/digital banking, credit operations etc.) while introducing process digitization

# Internships

SEED CSR April 2019

Worked on annual social audit & sustainability report of a youth skilling project undertaken by SEED CSR on behalf of Delhi
Aviation Fuel Facility Private Limited (DAFFPL). Initiated post-placement analysis for project efficiency & long-term impact

#### National CSR Awards (Field Verification Professional)

**April 2019** 

 Assisted as an independent expert in field verification of two finalist organizations for the National Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) Award by Ministry of Corporate Affairs, Govt. of India

## M.A. Dissertation (Workplace Bullying: Changing Forms of Bullying, Their Impact and Coping Mechanisms)

**April 2019** 

• The research aimed to study prevalence, nature and impact of bullying in organizational setups, using in-depth narrative interviews. Major findings relate to the need for a more exhaustive definition of bullying, its correlation with engagement, low reporting of such incidents and how targets cope

#### **Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Ltd.**

Dec 2018 - Feb 2019

Conducted & analyzed an Employee Happiness Survey amongst non-management factory staff at HPCL Refinery

Bajaj Auto Ltd. Sept 2018 – Oct 2018

• Designed an Employee Engagement Framework based on organizational challenges ascertained by qualitative interviews. The framework outlined focus areas based on job role, gender, demographics.

#### **Deloitte Consulting Pvt. Ltd**

June 2018 - July 2018

Undertook a 3-year trend analysis of annual spends on employees. Leveraged diverse metrics to provide actionable insights

#### Larsen & Toubro Infotech (LTI)

Dec 2017 - Feb 2018

 Designed a simulated, e-based Competency Assessment Tool for Managers which mapped their proficiency on various competencies and identified potential training domains by leveraging text mining

#### Protolab Electrotechnologies Pvt. Ltd.

July 2017 - Oct 2017

- Assisted in organization structure re-design & policy changes for reducing absenteeism and indifference at workplace
- Created an HR manual for formalization of various processes like hiring, performance management and leaves management

Awards	
2024	- Awarded for 'Building Shared Success' at Reckitt
2022	- Applause Award, Deloitte USI
2021	- 'COVID Warrior' Award at Deloitte USI
2020	- Special Recognition Award, Deloitte USI ch
2019	- Applause Award, Deloitte USI
2019	- National Institute of Personnel Management (NIPM) Silver Medal
2017-2019	- Institute Gold Medal and S. Kalsi Shield to the Best Student, Master of Arts (TISS)
2017-2019	- Mrs. S.R. Panakal Shield to the Best Student in Fieldwork, Master of Arts (TISS)
2017-2019	- NTPC Gold Medal to the Best Girl Student, Master of Arts by National Thermal Power Corporation Ltd.
2017-2019	- S.D. Marathe Endowment Prize for Best Student by National Institute of Labour Management Trust NILM)
2017-2019	- M.K. Tata Prize to the Best Student, Master of Arts

#### Certifications & Co-curriculars

## **Certifications/ Workshops**

- Facilitation Skills Certification, WeAreIdeas Consulting & 3M
- Co-facilitator, Leadership Development Workshop, Leaders Track Consulting
- Student Coordinator, Assessment Center, TISS

# **Case Study Competitions**

- Campus Finalist, TBLA- HR Case Study by TAS
- Campus Finalist, Interrobang- HR Case Study by ITC

### **Positions of Responsibility**

Co-founder, HR Incubation Cell at TISS (2019)

Organized the 1st StartUp Summit & launched Incubation Cell

# Member, HRM&LR Forum (2017-19)

 Organized annual management festival of TISS, Mumbai.
 Coordinator for management conclave featuring renowned leaders and international awardees

#### Editor, Aayam (2010-14)

- · Core team editor of University Literary magazine
- Organized annual literary fest of Banasthali University